<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Letter on Mr Ash Co</title>
    <link>/categories/letter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Letter on Mr Ash Co</description>
    <image>
      <title>Mr Ash Co</title>
      <url>/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/letter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Curious</title>
      <link>/curious/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/curious/</guid>
      <description>“I’m curious,” has become my favourite phrase to use in conversation. Curiosity is pretty awesome. It draws us to people, places and interesting things. It can influence important decisions and spark lifelong pathways. Let’s dive into curiosity more.
Hi, I’m Ash, a 27 y/o cybersec enthusiast journaling my journey on productivity &amp;amp; hacking. You’ve received a copy of the Monthly Monitor as you subscribed via the site or accessed a product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Won</title>
      <link>/i-won/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/i-won/</guid>
      <description>We’ve made it to October so let’s recap last month and catch up. Here’s a quick story I wanted to share with you about my first coding competition. Disclaimer, you’ve received this newsletter as you subscribed to Mr Ash .co. Note, the August newsletter wasn’t published via email but is now live.
I Won My First Coding Competition It’s early July and I’m scrolling Discord where I find myself on the W3Schools server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFK Aug</title>
      <link>/afk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/afk/</guid>
      <description>Hi friend,
Are you stressed? Most people are despite the ease of modern living. What&amp;rsquo;s something we can do to combat work-life stresses? Disclaimer, you’ve received this newsletter as you’ve subscribed to Mr Ash.co. Note, this month has a shortened newsletter.
AFK Away From Keyboard (AFK), coined by PC gamers to quickly chat “I’m getting food, don&amp;rsquo;t kill me in game” or something similar. I still use AFK today in work meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biz Plan</title>
      <link>/biz-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/biz-plan/</guid>
      <description>[Note] This month&amp;rsquo;s newsletter is self indulgent as it discusses my goals and plans.
It&amp;rsquo;s taken me 6 years to start uploading regular videos to YouTube, so it&amp;rsquo;s time for a plan. Here&amp;rsquo;s my brand/business plan, and shout out to my wife for helping me, these things are hard.
Hi, my name&amp;rsquo;s Ash, I&amp;rsquo;m 27 and a cyber security enthusiast sharing my journey. You’ve received this newsletter as you subscribed via my website or downloaded a freebie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Cyber</title>
      <link>/learn-cyber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learn-cyber/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s look back at the last 31 days, discuss the best way to learn cyber security and I’ll share a new project I’m working on. Disclaimer, you’ve received this newsletter as you subscribed to Mr Ash .co.
the BEST way to learn CyberSec?! If you want into CyberSec then get into Capture The Flags (CTFs), simple. CTFs are gamified learning, I mean, why do people spend so many hours playing video games?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
