<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacking on Mr Ash Co</title>
    <link>/tags/hacking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hacking on Mr Ash Co</description>
    <image>
      <title>Mr Ash Co</title>
      <url>/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/hacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>100 Days Of Hacking</title>
      <link>/100daysofhacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/100daysofhacking/</guid>
      <description>Programming, terminals, networking, and penetration testing. There’s a lot to love in computer hacking.
Are you learning to hack?
Maybe you’ve started but can’t keep motivated or you might not know where to start, let’s fix that!
Here’s 100 days of hacking, a flexible learning path to keep you on track.
Are you in? Yes, good, let’s go!
*Disclaimer, this is designed for self-paced learning and uses multiple resources from various creators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crack The Hash TryHackMe Walkthrough</title>
      <link>/crack-the-hash-tryhackme-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crack-the-hash-tryhackme-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>Let’s tackle Crack The Hash, another TryHackMe room full of hash-cracking challenges.
If you’d like a video walkthrough, then see the linked video below for a full guide to Crack The Hash.
Quickly, what is a hash and hashing in general?
“Hashing serves the purpose of ensuring integrity, i.e. making it so that if something is changed you can know that it’s changed. Technically, hashing takes arbitrary input and produce a fixed-length string…” — Daniel Miessler, Hashing vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TryHackMe Network Services 1 Part 2 Telnet</title>
      <link>/tryhackme-network-services-1-part-2-telnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tryhackme-network-services-1-part-2-telnet/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to TryHackMe Network Services Walkthrough Part 2, oh yeah! Let’s learn, then enumerate and exploit a variety of network services and misconfigurations, second up is telnet. Watch this Network Services Walkthrough for TryHackMe’s room, Part 2 Telnet.
Task 5 Understanding Telnet Questions:
What is Telnet? application protocol What has slowly replaced Telnet? ssh How would you connect to a Telnet server with the IP 10.10.10.3 on port 23? telnet 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TryHackMe Network Services 1 Part 3 FTP</title>
      <link>/tryhackme-network-services-1-part-3-ftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tryhackme-network-services-1-part-3-ftp/</guid>
      <description>Let’s go, TryHackMe Network Services Walkthrough Part 3, welcome! Step 1 learn, step 2 enumerate, and step 3 exploit… but what? Well, a variety of network services and misconfigurations of course, this time it’s FTP. Watch the Network Services Walkthrough for TryHackMe’s room, Part 3 FTP.
Task 8 Understanding FTP Questions:
What communications model does FTP use? client-server What’s the standard FTP port? 21 How many modes of FTP connection are there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackers Learning Path</title>
      <link>/learning-path-for-beginner-hacker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learning-path-for-beginner-hacker/</guid>
      <description>Want to hack computers? But what is hacking and how do people learn it?
Here’s a vetted list of resources to learn computer hacking. Starting out is hard work, so that’s why I’ve put this list together, to help demystify hacking for you.
The good news is anyone (including you) can learn to hack, and in even better news, it’s a lot of fun. All you need is effort and time, most of the resources are completely free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TryHackMe Network Services Walkthrough SMB Part 1/3</title>
      <link>/tryhackme-network-services-walkthrough-smb-part-1-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tryhackme-network-services-walkthrough-smb-part-1-3/</guid>
      <description>Task 1 Get Connected Questions
Ready? Let’s get going! – No answer needed, carry on. Offline checklist to track your learning path, become a great hacker and stay on task.
Task 2 Understanding SMB What does SMB stand for? – Server Message Block What type of protocol is SMB? – response-request What do clients connect to servers using? – TCP/IP What systems does Samba run on? – Unix Task 3 Enumerating SMB Run nmap scan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TryHackMe Nmap Room Notes</title>
      <link>/tryhackme-nmap-room-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tryhackme-nmap-room-notes/</guid>
      <description>Are you going through TryHackMe’s Nmap Room? Did you forget to take notes? I got you covered. Here are my Nmap room notes from TryHackMe, use them as much as you need!
Disclaimer, this is written in shorthand format, meaning, full sentences and proper grammar are always not used. For a full writeup, see TryHackMe Nmap Walkthrough, for help with Linux, see Quick Start Guide.
Task 1 Deploy &amp;amp; Task 2 Introduction Ports: allow multiple network services, ensure correct device communication, 65535 total.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Fundamentals 2 - TryHackMe Walkthrough</title>
      <link>/linux-fundamentals-2-tryhackme-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/linux-fundamentals-2-tryhackme-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>So you’re learning Linux aye? Welcome aboard!
Here’s the Linux Fundamentals 2 Walkthrough from TryHackMe. Let’s take a look at some of the fundamentals of Linux including some more commands, ssh, bash scripting and more.
There’s lots to love in Linux, I hope you learn something here on your Linux journey! Enjoy TryHackMe’s Linux Fundamentals 2.
Disclaimer, for more, see Linux Fundamentals 1, Linux Fundamentals 3 and Linux Quick Start Guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Fundamentals 3 TryHackMe Walkthrough</title>
      <link>/linux-fundamentals-3-tryhackme-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/linux-fundamentals-3-tryhackme-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Linux Fundamentals 3 TryHackMe Walkthrough, the finale of the Linux Fundamental rooms on TryHackMe.
Let’s learn some Linux skills and common utilities around automation, package management, and service/application logging. Are you keen? Yeah!
Let’s go on with Linux Fundamentals 3 TryHackMe Walkthrough.
Disclaimer, see Linux Fundamentals Part 1 and Linux Fundamentals Part 2 for more. Also, see the video walkthrough too:
Task 1 Introduction &amp;amp; Task 2 Deploy Your Linux Machine Alright, you should be a pro with connecting to TryHackMe’s VPN via OpenVPN and ssh-ing into the TryHackMe user via the provided ip address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Out In Cyber Security</title>
      <link>/starting-out-in-cyber-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/starting-out-in-cyber-security/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few years, the term Cyber Security has become more popular.
Google trends show it’s searched now more than ever before in history. It’s currently Australia’s top hiring priority.
What’s Cyber Security? And why is it so popular? Let’s do some research and find out!
Disclaimer: I’m not a Cyber Security expert, I’m a student of IT and love sharing what I’m learning or have learnt.
What’s Cyber Security?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
