<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Note on Mr Ash Co</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/note/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Note on Mr Ash Co</description>
    <image>
      <title>Mr Ash Co</title>
      <url>//localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>//localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/note/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TryHackMe Nmap Room Notes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/tryhackme-nmap-room-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/tryhackme-nmap-room-notes/</guid>
      <description>Are you going through TryHackMe’s Nmap Room? Did you forget to take notes? I got you covered. Here are my Nmap room notes from TryHackMe, use them as much as you need!
Disclaimer, this is written in shorthand format, meaning, full sentences and proper grammar are always not used. For a full writeup, see TryHackMe Nmap Walkthrough, for help with Linux, see Quick Start Guide.
Task 1 Deploy &amp;amp; Task 2 Introduction Ports: allow multiple network services, ensure correct device communication, 65535 total.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CompTIA A&#43; Study Notes (220-1101)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/comptia-a-plus-study-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/comptia-a-plus-study-notes/</guid>
      <description>Installing Hardware and Display Components Hardware and Device Replacement RAM: system memory or desk of PC, fast access, low amount = lower access speeds, volatile. Storage: file cabinet of PC, slower access, static (non-volatile). Check MoBo user guide to ensure RAM amount, form-factor etc. GPU/Video Card: processes video and connects to external monitors. CPU: brain of PC. DC Jack Replacement Research – https://youtu.be/zFuu8LSaAQE
Hard Drive Migration SSD: non-volatile flash memory for storage, faster, reliable, less power, quieter, smaller.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
